Gosh, I drank way too much!
Boże, za dużo wypiłam.
Well, I should get going.
To ja już pójdę.
Hey, wait.
Poczekaj.
What's the hurry?
Spieszysz się dokądś?
Hey, Katou-san, you're so handsome and dependable.
Katou-san, jesteś przystojny i można na tobie polegać.
-You've put me on the spot. -You're really my type.
- Stawiasz mnie w niezręcznej sytuacji. - Podobasz mi się.
Hey, do you know about this?
Słyszałeś o tym?
Oops, sorry.
Przepraszam.
I didn't mean to pull out three--
Nie chciałam wyrwać trzech…
No way.
To niemożliwe.
You've put me on the spot.
Niezręczna sytuacja.
The hair gave me away.
Zdradziły mnie włosy.
Help me out.
Pomóż mi.
I don't care for meat that contains alcohol.
Nie chcę mięsa, które ma w sobie alkohol.
AUTHOR: HITOSHI IWAAKI
AUTOR: HITOSHI IWAAKI
You saved my life.
Uratowałeś mnie.
THE BLUE BIRD
NIEBIESKI PTAK
I can't believe he did something like that.
Nie wierzę, że to zrobił.
How are Izumi and I similar?
Jestem podobny do Izumiego?
I mean, whatever you're sensing
To, co czujesz,
might be weird wavelengths given off by dangerous guys like him.
to mogą być sygnały wysyłane przez takich niebezpiecznych gości jak on.
But Izumi? Could he be…
Czy Izumi jest…
You shouldn't do that without warning.
Nie rób tego bez ostrzeżenia.
Sorry.
Przepraszam.
If you want to pluck one of my hairs, go ahead.
Śmiało, wyrwij mi włos, jeśli chcesz.
Really?
Serio?
Then I will.
To zrobię to.
Satisfied?
Zadowolona?
Wait!
Poczekaj!
Remember how you warned me before about Shimada?
Pamiętasz, jak ostrzegałeś mnie przed Shimadą?
Did you know who he was from the start?
Od początku wiedziałeś, kim był?
No, not really.
Niezupełnie.
I guess that makes sense.
Ma to sens.
You wouldn't know a mass murderer like him.
Skąd miałbyś znać seryjnego mordercę?
Why the serious look?
Coś ty taki poważny?
This girl's special.
Ta dziewczyna jest wyjątkowa.
Maybe I should just tell her everything.
Może o wszystkim jej powiem?
But Migi's awake.
Ale Migi nie śpi.
Shinichi, I know what you're thinking,
Shinichi, wiem, o czym myślisz,
but that female is no ally of mine.
ale ona nie jest moją sojuszniczką.
Your name is Kana, right?
Jesteś Kana, tak?
Um, yeah.
Tak.
You said you have some mysterious telepathic ability to sense me,
Mówiłaś, że potrafisz mnie wyczuć.
but even if you feel that I'm close, you should stay away.
Gdy ci się wydaje, że jestem blisko, nie zbliżaj się.
Why?
Dlaczego?
You might run into a monster.
Bo możesz spotkać potwora.
-A monster? -Yeah.
- Potwora? - Tak.
Why do you think that?
Dlaczego tak myślisz?
Aren't you a normal human being?
Nie jesteś zwykłym człowiekiem?
Of course I am.
Jasne, że jestem.
Then, if I get that feeling from anyone, I'll just pluck out one of their hairs.
Jeśli kogoś tak wyczuję, wyrwę mu włos. Będę wiedziała, czy to potwór…
No! You can't do that!
Nie możesz tego robić!
What's wrong?
Co się dzieje?
Sorry.
Przepraszam.
But seriously, it's too dangerous.
Ale serio, to bardzo niebezpieczne.
You're worried about me?
Martwisz się o mnie?
That kind of makes me happy.
Cieszę się.
Shinichi.
Shinichi.
I need to talk to you.
Musimy porozmawiać.
Oh, I just remembered something I have to do.
Zapomniałem, że muszę coś załatwić.
Sorry, later.
- Do zobaczenia. - Co?
Oh, you're…
Jesteś…
Hello.
Cześć.
Shinichi, don't talk to that female anymore.
Nie rozmawiaj więcej z tą dziewczyną.
I can't agree to that.
Muszę.
If I leave her be, she'll get herself into danger for sure.
Jeśli ją tak zostawię, coś się jej stanie.
But the way you talk to her gives her all kinds of hints.
Mówisz jej rzeczy, przez które może cię zdemaskować.
I'll be more careful.
Będę uważał.
I expect nothing less.
Mam nadzieję.
Um, I know asking you this out of nowhere might seem weird, but…
To może dziwne pytanie, ale…
What is it?
O co chodzi?
Don't you think Izumi-kun has changed a lot from before?
Nie uważasz, że Izumi-kun bardzo się zmienił?
It's hard for me to compare.
Trudno mi powiedzieć.
It's not like I see him that often.
Nie widuję go zbyt często.
I'm talking about when you first met him compared to now.
Jest taki jak wtedy, gdy go poznałaś?
Did you guys have a fight? You like him, right?
Pokłóciliście się? Podoba ci się on?
He's just different somehow.
Zmienił się.
It's not noticeable when we're talking, but…
Nie widać tego, gdy rozmawiamy, ale…
He saved my life, too.
Mnie też uratował.
Saved your life? You have dreams like that, too?
Uratował cię? Też ci się śni?
Huh? Dreams?
Co? Śni?
Uh, I mean…
To znaczy…
I can't see any difference.
Nie zauważyłam różnicy.
In a way, I feel like he was always like that.
Wydaje mi się, że zawsze taki był.
He kind of has this ferocity to him.
Ma w sobie taką dzikość.
If you don't get that mopey look off your face,
Jeśli będziesz miała taką smutną minę, to go stracisz.
Maybe I still have a chance.
Może mam szansę?
I'll be back in ten.
Będę za dziesięć minut.
All right.
Dobrze.
But couldn't you have tried to blend in a little?
Musisz tak bardzo się wyróżniać?
The clothes will get soiled anyway.
I tak się pobrudzę.
You need something?
Czego chcesz?
How many of you are inside?
Ilu jest was w środku?
You stupid or something?
Głupi jesteś czy co?
Beat it before you get yourself hurt!
Spadaj, bo oberwiesz!
I see.
Rozumiem.
The yakuza are very belligerent, aren't they?
Członkowie jakuzy są agresywni.
Sometimes you run into people who get the silly idea
Czasami spotykamy ludzi, którzy głupio myślą,
that the yakuza can't harm civilians because of anti-gang laws!
że jakuza nie krzywdzi obywateli, bo zabrania jej tego prawo!
Who are you?
Kim jesteś?
What?
Co się dzieje?
Who the hell is he?
Kto to, do cholery?
What's the matter?
Co jest?
Come at me.
Atakujcie mnie.
That's one.
Pierwszy.
You monster!
Potworze!
Two.
Drugi.
We got him.
Mamy go.
Three, huh.
Trzeci.
No way.
To niemożliwe.
I failed to avoid three.
Nie uniknąłem trzeciego.
I guess that's about par.
Więc mamy remis.
Monster.
Potwór.
What the hell are you here for?
Czego chcesz, do cholery?
This is an experiment
To eksperyment.
to see how far we can go against a group with guns and edged weapons.
Chcę sprawdzić, jak sobie radzimy z grupą uzbrojonych ludzi.
Did something happen?
Coś się stało?
There's a body over there. His head's been bashed in.
Tam leży ciało z rozwaloną głową.
I just heard gunshots, too.
Słyszałem też strzały.
Seriously?
Naprawdę?
Hey, he's running away!
Ucieka!
After him!
Za nim!
Huh? He's gone.
Co? Zniknął.
That's weird.
To dziwne.
I know he came this way.
Pobiegł tutaj.
Drop it.
Zostawmy go.
We wouldn't want to get drawn into a gang war.
Nie chcemy mieszać się w wojnę gangów.
Should we at least call the cops?
Może wezwijmy policję?
I'm sure someone already has.
Pewnie ktoś już to zrobił.
What is it?
O co chodzi?
Oh, it's just that you look very different from before.
Wygląda pan inaczej.
A massacre at a yakuza office.
Masakra w biurze jakuzy.
They say there were 22 casualties,
Zginęły 22 osoby.
which includes everyone who was at the office.
Wszyscy, którzy byli w biurze.
A lot of scary things are happening one after another.
Dzieje się wiele strasznych rzeczy.
Yeah.
Tak.
Was it a parasite?
To pasożyt?
No, they shouldn't kill like this for reasons other than feeding.
Nie, one zabijają tylko po to, żeby się pożywić.
They stated that they will release
Chce pokazać nagranie,
security camera footage of a male suspect seen fleeing the scene.
na którym jest podejrzany uciekający z miejsca zbrodni.
You didn't hold back at all.
Nie hamowałeś się.
It was good exercise, boss.
To było dobre ćwiczenie, szefie.
Izumi-kun!
Izumi-kun!
Thanks for coming.
Dziękuję, że przyszłaś.
No problem.
Nie ma sprawy.
Thanks for the invite.
Dziękuję za zaproszenie.
-What are you up for? -Let's watch a movie, for starters.
- Co zaplanowałeś? - Najpierw obejrzymy film.
Okay!
Dobrze!
SADAKO 2D - BLOOD WILL BE DEFEATED
SADAKO 2D
I still have dreams about what happened that day.
Nadal śni mi się to, co się wtedy stało.
Even after I wake up, I can't stop shaking.
Gdy się budzę, to się trzęsę.
Does that ever happen to you, Izumi-kun?
Też tak masz?
Sometimes.
Czasami.
But by the time morning comes, I've forgotten most of it.
Ale rano o wszystkim zapominam.
That must be nice.
Fajnie tak.
My dreams are so vivid and colorful that I remember them pretty clearly.
Moje sny są takie żywe i kolorowe, że dobrze je pamiętam.
My friend once told me this.
Kolega powiedział mi kiedyś,
He said to think of people like cattle and pigs.
żeby myśleć o ludziach jak o bydle i świniach.
When you do that,
Wtedy zrozumiesz, że ludzie codziennie jedzą zwierzęta,
so you shouldn't have anything to be afraid of after that.
więc nie ma się czego bać.
That's unusual.
Ciekawe stwierdzenie.
What kind of person is he?
- Jakim człowiekiem jest ten kolega? - Jakim jest człowiekiem?
I wonder if your friend's one reason you've changed.
Ciekawe, czy to przez niego się zmieniłeś.
I don't think so.
Chyba nie.
Oh, sorry.
Przepraszam.
You've changed, but it's nothing you need to worry about.
Zmieniłeś się, ale się tym nie przejmuj.
I wonder if it's from back then.
Ciekawe, czy to było wtedy.
Maybe Izumi-kun hasn't really come back since he left on that trip.
Może Izumi-kun nie wrócił z tej wycieczki.
Izumi-kun, remember when your dad got injured while on a trip and…
Izumi-kun, pamiętasz, jak twój tata miał wypadek na wycieczce i…
Let's go.
Chodźmy.
I guess I shouldn't have asked him about it.
Niepotrzebnie o to zapytałam.
Oh. So cute!
Ale słodziak!
Come here!
Chodź tutaj!
That must be his mom.
To chyba jego mama.
Must be.
Pewnie tak.
Are they strays?
Są bezdomne?
I guess not.
Chyba nie.
She's wearing a collar.
Ma obrożę.
Oh, Izumi-kun?
Izumi-kun?
It's a nice day.
Ładny dzień.
It's not even that cold.
Jest całkiem ciepło.
You're talking like an old man, Izumi-kun.
Mówisz jak staruszek.
Hey, that was mean.
To było niemiłe.
Mommy!
Mamo!
Hey, Mommy!
Mamusiu!
Wait for me!
Poczekaj!
Come on. Let's go.
Chodźmy.
Hurry up, now.
Pospiesz się.
Stupid Mommy!
Głupia mama!
Why…
Dlaczego…
Why would you say that?
Dlaczego tak mówisz?
I hate you, Mommy!
Nienawidzę cię, mamo!
Hey, it's not like…
Przecież ja…
I hope you die!
Obyś umarła!
Come on. Let's go.
Chodźmy już.
Izumi-kun?
Izumi-kun?
A hole.
Dziura.
There's a hole.
Mam dziurę.
A hole?
Dziurę?
What's wrong?
Co się stało? Dobrze się czujesz?
I had a hard time breathing all of a sudden.
Miałem trudności z oddychaniem.
Maybe I'm just getting old.
Może się starzeję.
Oh, come on. You're really acting like an old man now.
Teraz zachowujesz się jak staruszek.
Sometimes, I feel as though my body's being ripped apart.
Czasami czuję, jakby moje ciało rozrywało się na kawałki.
But that feeling goes away after a while.
Ale po chwili to uczucie mija.
That's when I feel as though some part of Migi's become a part of my heart.
Wtedy czuję, że część Migiego jest częścią mojego serca.
But I still do like her.
Ale lubię ją.
I really care about her.
Zależy mi na niej.
That feeling is mine alone.
To uczucie jest tylko moje.
When things are going well with me and her,
Gdy miło spędzam z nią czas,
I always wish you would stay asleep,
chciałbym, żebyś spał,
Migi.
Migi.
See you later.
Do zobaczenia.
Okay.
Pa.
You're Izumi Shinichi-kun, right?
Jesteś Izumi Shinichi-kun, prawda?
If only…
Szkoda…
If only we'd gotten closer much sooner.
Szkoda, że wcześniej się do siebie nie zbliżyliśmy.
I could believe that you are Izumi-kun
Wtedy bez wątpienia wierzyłabym,
without any doubt.
że jesteś Izumi-kun.
You stupid girl.
Idiotko.
You knew this from the start.
Od początku o tym wiedziałaś.
But…
Ale…
Why are you going to the trouble of seeing her?
Po co chcesz się z nią spotkać?
I can't ignore her when she says it's the last favor she'll ever ask.
Powiedziała, że ma ostatnią prośbę. Nie mogę tego olać.
I find this incomprehensible.
Coś mi tu nie gra.
Maybe I'm a little early.
Może jestem za wcześnie?
Shinichi, I sense my kind.
Wyczuwam moich.
Not just one but three.
Nie jednego, a trzech.
No, five?
Albo pięciu.
How many are there?
To ilu ich jest?
They're that way.
Są tam.
What needs to change is our individual mentality.
Musimy zmienić nasz sposób myślenia.
Debating global environmental conservation…
Debata na temat ochrony środowiska…
It appears they are aware of our presence, but they aren't taking any action.
Wiedzą, że tu jesteśmy, ale nic nie robią.
I'm suddenly realizing
Jesteśmy jak Kitaro i jego tata z takiego anime.
They are approximately 60 meters away.
Są 60 metrów przed nami.
Eight of them total.
Jest ich ośmiu.
Two are close to the ground and six are high up.
Dwóch stoi nisko, a sześciu wysoko.
Perhaps on a stand of some sort.
Są na podeście.
Would you be willing to forego your cars in order to prevent polluting the air?
Zrezygnujecie z samochodów, żeby nie zanieczyszczać powietrza?
It is difficult in the extreme to consider reversing
Trudno cofnąć postęp, który zrobiliśmy jako cywilizacja?
However, if we do not, at least in some aspects…
Jeśli tego nie zrobimy…
The six of them up there. They're all parasites?
Cała szóstka to pasożyty?
Two below, too.
Dwóch niżej też.
At this distance, it is difficult to identify them,
Nie zidentyfikują nas, chyba że nawiążemy kontakt wzrokowy.
Did he see us?
Widział nas?
But in this crowd…
Ale w tym tłumie…
He saw us.
Widział nas.
Our eyes met,
Spojrzeliśmy na siebie,
but they do not seem to be very interested in us.
ale nie jest nami zainteresowany.
Now that we've seen a rare sight,
Widzieliśmy coś niezwykłego.
let's get out of here for now.
Teraz stąd uciekajmy.
Yeah.
Jasne.
A parasite running for mayor?
Pasożyt chce być burmistrzem?
What are they planning?
Co one kombinują?
Oh! Izumi!
Izumi!
Why are you here?
Co tu robisz?
Why?
A co?
I live in this neighborhood,
Mieszkam w tej okolicy.
and I'm the one who asked you to meet me here.
Chciałam się tu z tobą spotkać.
Oh. Right.
No tak.
…but it is at the municipal level that
…problemy środowiskowe można rozwiązywać na szczeblu gminnym,
rather than at the national level.
a nie krajowym.
This isn't good.
Niedobrze.
Next time, "Kokoro."
Kolejny odcinek: „Kokoro”.